<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conference | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/conference/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Conference</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 10:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu2517494180984873850.png</url>
      <title>Conference</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/conference/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting at Henry Ford Health Annual Research Symposium: Body Image Distress Intervention (2024)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/henry-ford-symposium-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/henry-ford-symposium-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Fall 2024, I presented a research poster at the &lt;strong&gt;Henry Ford Health Annual Research Symposium&lt;/strong&gt;, based on my work as a Clinical Research Coordinator in the Department of Otolaryngology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The poster was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Effects of a Brief Cognitive Behavioral Treatment vs Attention Control for Body Image-Related Distress Among Head and Neck Cancer Survivors: A Multi-Site RCT.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study was a randomized controlled trial comparing a brief CBT intervention to an attention control condition, aimed at reducing distress related to appearance changes following cancer treatment. I collaborated with a multidisciplinary team across several institutions, contributing to data collection, protocol fidelity, and patient coordination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenting at this internal symposium gave me the chance to share results with clinicians, researchers, and trainees, and to see how local innovations in patient-centered research were making an impact across disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience deepened my interest in clinical trials and behavioral intervention research, especially where psychological science meets real-world application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AHNS at COSM 2024: Socioeconomic Factors and Equity in PROM Completion</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/ahns-cosm-equity-proms-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/ahns-cosm-equity-proms-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In May 2024, I presented a second clinical research poster at the &lt;strong&gt;American Head and Neck Society (AHNS)&lt;/strong&gt; track at &lt;strong&gt;COSM – Combined Otolaryngology Spring Meetings&lt;/strong&gt;. This work was conducted with the research team at &lt;strong&gt;Henry Ford Health&lt;/strong&gt; and focused on equity in cancer care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The poster, titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Socioeconomic Factors Impacting Equity in Completion of Patient-Reported Outcome Measures Among Patients with Head and Neck Cancer,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
investigated how variables like income, insurance status, and digital access affected PROM completion rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I contributed to the data analysis and presentation development alongside collaborators including Dr. Samantha Tam and colleagues across multiple institutions. This work reinforced the need to consider structural barriers in patient engagement and helped me appreciate the broader context of behavioral and psychosocial research within clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COSM was a dynamic, interdisciplinary venue — and presenting our findings there gave me the opportunity to engage with experts in otolaryngology, behavioral medicine, and implementation science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting at AHNS 2024: Enhancing PROM Engagement in Head and Neck Cancer</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/ahns-prom-engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/ahns-prom-engagement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2024, I co-presented a research poster at the &lt;strong&gt;American Head and Neck Society (AHNS) Annual Meeting&lt;/strong&gt;, based on work conducted during my time as a Clinical Research Coordinator at &lt;strong&gt;Henry Ford Health&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The poster was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enhancing PROM Engagement: A Mixed Methods Approach to Reminder Interventions and Patient Preferences in Head and Neck Cancer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was part of the &lt;strong&gt;BRIGHT Trial&lt;/strong&gt;, led by Dr. Samantha Tam, and aimed to identify strategies for improving completion rates and patient satisfaction with electronic patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs). My role involved coordinating study visits, managing REDCap data, and contributing to qualitative data synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation marked my first experience disseminating clinical research at a national conference. It offered an important perspective on translational science, bridging patient-centered care and behavioral health research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participating in this work expanded my methodological skills and deepened my appreciation for research that directly impacts patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting at the Midwest Cognitive Science Conference: Argumentative Writing and Belief Change (2023)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/midwest-cogsci-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/midwest-cogsci-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2023, I presented a research poster at the &lt;strong&gt;Midwest Cognitive Science Conference&lt;/strong&gt;, expanding on work I had previously shared at the Society for Text and Discourse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The poster, titled &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Beliefs Influence Argumentative Writing,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; continued our investigation into how belief change following persuasive reading impacts the way people write argumentative essays. This project was part of my ongoing work in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; at Grand Valley State University, led by Dr. Michael Wolfe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conference offered an exciting opportunity to engage with researchers from across the region, share findings in a more interactive format, and refine how I communicated the practical implications of our study. It also marked one of my final undergraduate research milestones before graduating and heading to graduate school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Events like this helped me solidify my identity as a researcher and gave me valuable experience presenting in academic spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting at the Society for Text and Discourse: Beliefs and Argumentative Writing (2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/society-text-discourse-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/society-text-discourse-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Summer 2022, I delivered my first oral presentation at an academic conference — the &lt;strong&gt;Annual Meeting of the Society for Text and Discourse&lt;/strong&gt;. This event, held virtually that year, brought together scholars interested in reading, discourse, and communication processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Belief Change After Reading Predicts Argumentative Essay Content.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research emerged from my work as an undergraduate researcher in the Social Cognition Lab at Grand Valley State University, under the mentorship of Dr. Michael Wolfe. We examined how changes in students&amp;rsquo; beliefs after reading persuasive texts influenced the structure and content of their argumentative essays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenting at this conference was an incredibly formative experience. It helped me build confidence in communicating my research, fielding questions from experts, and engaging with a broader academic community. It also affirmed my interest in pursuing graduate research in cognition, memory, and language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation was an early but pivotal step on my academic path.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belief Change and Persuasion: Poster Presentation at MPA 2022</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/mpa-belief-poster-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/mpa-belief-poster-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2022, I presented a poster at the &lt;strong&gt;Midwestern Psychological Association (MPA) Conference&lt;/strong&gt;, held in Chicago. The project was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Information About Past Beliefs Influences Current Beliefs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study explored how explicitly reminding individuals of their past beliefs affects their current evaluations of persuasive information. The poster was based on research I conducted in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; at Grand Valley State University with Dr. Michael Wolfe, and it contributed to our broader line of work on belief change, reading comprehension, and persuasive writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was one of my first in-person academic conferences, and I gained valuable experience discussing research with a broad audience of psychologists and students from across the Midwest. It also reinforced the importance of clear visual communication and thoughtful responses to audience questions — skills I’ve continued to develop in subsequent presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Scholars Day 2022 at GVSU: Belief Change and Persuasion Poster</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-scholars-day-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-scholars-day-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April 2022, I presented a research poster at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University’s Student Scholars Day&lt;/strong&gt;, a campus-wide event that showcases undergraduate research and creative work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My presentation was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Information About Past Beliefs Influences Current Beliefs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project examined how prompting individuals to recall their past beliefs before reading persuasive material could influence how strongly they endorse those beliefs afterward. It was part of my work in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; with Dr. Michael Wolfe and complemented our studies on belief revision and argumentative writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student Scholars Day offered a supportive environment to share work with students, faculty, and staff outside the psychology department. It also gave me an early chance to practice tailoring my research communication for diverse audiences — a skill that has been invaluable throughout my academic path.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Scholars Showcase 2021: Belief Change and Persuasion Talk at GVSU</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-summer-scholars-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-summer-scholars-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Summer 2021, I presented at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University’s Student Summer Scholars Showcase&lt;/strong&gt;, where I shared the results of my research project funded by a competitive undergraduate research grant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk, titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Information About Past Beliefs Influences Current Beliefs,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
explored how reflecting on previously held beliefs shapes the way individuals respond to persuasive texts and influences their reasoning and writing. This was part of my extended work in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; with Dr. Michael Wolfe, supported by the &lt;strong&gt;Student Summer Scholars Grant&lt;/strong&gt; from the Office of Undergraduate Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation was a major milestone in my development as a researcher. It gave me the chance to formally communicate my findings to faculty, administrators, and peers, and marked my first time delivering an academic talk based on independently developed research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience affirmed my desire to pursue graduate study and helped build the skills I continue to use in my current academic and professional presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Ageism Through Service Learning: Virtual Talk at GVSU Student Scholars Day (2021)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-ageism-virtual-talk-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-ageism-virtual-talk-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2021, I delivered a &lt;strong&gt;virtual talk&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University’s Student Scholars Day&lt;/strong&gt;, presenting findings from an independent study on educational interventions for reducing ageism in college students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Can Ageism Be Reduced by Service Learning Built Into a Lecture-Based Aging Course?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project, conducted under the guidance of Dr. Jing Chen, investigated how a lecture course on aging—when paired with service-learning opportunities—impacted students’ attitudes toward older adults. This research combined my interests in gerontology, education, and social attitudes, and was part of a growing body of work aimed at addressing bias through curriculum design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first formal presentation focused on aging and intergenerational attitudes, and it helped solidify my interest in aging research and its relevance to real-world social issues. The experience also helped me adapt to presenting in virtual formats — a skill that became essential during the pandemic years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Research Experience: Exercise Science Poster at GVSU Student Scholars Day (2019)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-exercise-science-poster-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-exercise-science-poster-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2019, during my first year as an undergraduate at Grand Valley State University, I participated in &lt;strong&gt;Student Scholars Day&lt;/strong&gt; as a co-author on a research poster in the &lt;strong&gt;Exercise Science Lab&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Effect of Different Pre-Exercise Treatments on Power Output.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working under the mentorship of faculty in the Exercise Science program, I helped collect and analyze data examining how various warm-up interventions influenced athletic performance. This early exposure to the research process gave me foundational skills in study design, teamwork, and public presentation — all of which proved valuable as I transitioned into cognitive psychology research later in my undergraduate career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although outside my current academic focus, this project introduced me to the world of empirical inquiry and shaped my confidence in pursuing more complex research in later years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
