<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exercise Science | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/exercise-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/exercise-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Exercise Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 11:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Exercise Science</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/exercise-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Research Experience: Exercise Science Poster at GVSU Student Scholars Day (2019)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-exercise-science-poster-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-exercise-science-poster-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2019, during my first year as an undergraduate at Grand Valley State University, I participated in &lt;strong&gt;Student Scholars Day&lt;/strong&gt; as a co-author on a research poster in the &lt;strong&gt;Exercise Science Lab&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Effect of Different Pre-Exercise Treatments on Power Output.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working under the mentorship of faculty in the Exercise Science program, I helped collect and analyze data examining how various warm-up interventions influenced athletic performance. This early exposure to the research process gave me foundational skills in study design, teamwork, and public presentation — all of which proved valuable as I transitioned into cognitive psychology research later in my undergraduate career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although outside my current academic focus, this project introduced me to the world of empirical inquiry and shaped my confidence in pursuing more complex research in later years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Undergraduate Research at GVSU (2018–2019)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/starting-undergrad-research-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/starting-undergrad-research-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Fall 2018, I began my first research experience as an undergraduate student at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt;, joining the &lt;strong&gt;Exercise Science Lab&lt;/strong&gt; during my first year on campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project, titled &lt;em&gt;“The Effect of Different Pre-Exercise Treatments on Power Output,”&lt;/em&gt; investigated how warm-up interventions influence athletic performance. I contributed to data collection, participant coordination, and experimental setup — all of which gave me early exposure to the scientific method and the collaborative nature of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although my academic interests would later shift toward psychology and cognitive science, this experience was a formative milestone. It helped me build confidence in asking research questions, thinking critically about experimental design, and presenting findings — skills that would become central to my later work in psychology, aging, and memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also my first experience presenting research publicly at GVSU’s Student Scholars Day in 2019 — an event that helped launch my passion for research communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
