<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education Milestone | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/education-milestone/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/education-milestone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Education Milestone</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 10:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Education Milestone</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/education-milestone/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduating from Grand Valley State University (2021)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-graduation-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-graduation-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2021, I graduated from &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt; with a &lt;strong&gt;Bachelor of Science in Psychology&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;minor in Applied Statistics&lt;/strong&gt;. My time at GVSU was foundational to my academic and research development — both in and out of the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at GVSU, I was involved in multiple research projects across psychology and exercise science, earned the &lt;strong&gt;Undergraduate Research Scholar designation&lt;/strong&gt;, and completed a &lt;strong&gt;Student Summer Scholars Grant&lt;/strong&gt;. I was also honored to receive several awards, including the &lt;strong&gt;Excellence-in-a-Discipline Award&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;Robert Hendersen Leadership Award&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Outstanding Creative Achievement&lt;/strong&gt; from the Honors College.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through these experiences, I discovered my passion for research on belief, cognition, aging, and emotional memory — and developed a long-term interest in combining psychological science with computational methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GVSU was where I first learned to design studies, analyze data, present at conferences, and write for publication — and it laid the groundwork for everything that followed in graduate school.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Undergraduate Research at GVSU (2018–2019)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/starting-undergrad-research-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/starting-undergrad-research-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Fall 2018, I began my first research experience as an undergraduate student at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt;, joining the &lt;strong&gt;Exercise Science Lab&lt;/strong&gt; during my first year on campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project, titled &lt;em&gt;“The Effect of Different Pre-Exercise Treatments on Power Output,”&lt;/em&gt; investigated how warm-up interventions influence athletic performance. I contributed to data collection, participant coordination, and experimental setup — all of which gave me early exposure to the scientific method and the collaborative nature of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although my academic interests would later shift toward psychology and cognitive science, this experience was a formative milestone. It helped me build confidence in asking research questions, thinking critically about experimental design, and presenting findings — skills that would become central to my later work in psychology, aging, and memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also my first experience presenting research publicly at GVSU’s Student Scholars Day in 2019 — an event that helped launch my passion for research communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
