<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Award | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/award/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/award/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Award</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 12:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Award</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/award/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awarded the President’s Fellowship at Georgia Tech (2024–2028)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/presidents-fellowship-gt-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/presidents-fellowship-gt-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2024, I was honored to receive the &lt;strong&gt;President’s Fellowship&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Georgia Institute of Technology&lt;/strong&gt;, awarded to the &lt;strong&gt;top 10 percent of incoming doctoral students&lt;/strong&gt; across the Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fellowship provides four years of supplemental funding and professional development support. It recognizes not only academic and research potential but also leadership and service contributions. For me, it marked a tremendous vote of confidence in my graduate research goals and my commitment to the study of aging, memory, and emotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This support has given me the flexibility to pursue interdisciplinary work at the intersection of cognitive psychology and natural language processing, and has allowed me to focus deeply on developing both technical and theoretical expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m grateful to Georgia Tech for this opportunity and am working hard to make the most of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excellence-in-a-Discipline Award: Psychology at GVSU (2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/excellence-in-discipline-award-gvsu-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/excellence-in-discipline-award-gvsu-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2022, I was honored to receive the &lt;strong&gt;Excellence-in-a-Discipline Award&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt;, which recognizes one undergraduate student in each major who has demonstrated outstanding academic achievement and disciplinary engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was selected for this award within the &lt;strong&gt;Psychology Department&lt;/strong&gt;, based on my coursework, research contributions, and professional development activities. At the time, I was actively engaged in multiple research projects and had recently presented at both campus and regional conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recognition was a meaningful capstone to my undergraduate work. It reflected not only academic success but also the mentorship, collaboration, and hands-on experiences that shaped my growth as a student and emerging researcher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receiving this award gave me further confidence as I prepared to transition to graduate school and pursue more advanced research opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outstanding Creative Achievement Award for Honors College Capstone (2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/creative-achievement-award-podcast-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/creative-achievement-award-podcast-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2022, I was honored to receive the &lt;strong&gt;Outstanding Creative Achievement Award&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;strong&gt;Frederik Meijer Honors College&lt;/strong&gt; at Grand Valley State University. This award recognized the top five senior capstone projects across the college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My project was a podcast series titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perspectives on Psilocybin: The Science and Mysticism of Magic Mushrooms.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series explored the historical, cultural, and scientific dimensions of psilocybin — from indigenous use and psychedelic therapy to neuroscience and public perception. It blended interviews, academic research, and narrative storytelling to bridge science communication and experiential knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This capstone project allowed me to combine academic inquiry with creative storytelling, sparking what would later become a deeper interest in &lt;strong&gt;transformative experiences&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;self-defining memory&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;interdisciplinary communication&lt;/strong&gt; — all of which continue to influence my graduate research trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The award was a meaningful affirmation of the value of creative, public-facing scholarship in psychology and cognitive science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Hendersen Leadership Award in Psychology (2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/henderson-leadership-award-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/henderson-leadership-award-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2022, I was awarded the &lt;strong&gt;Robert Hendersen Leadership Award&lt;/strong&gt; by the &lt;strong&gt;Psychology Department at Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt;. This departmental honor is presented annually to a student who has demonstrated outstanding leadership, service, and engagement within the academic and campus community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recognition reflected my roles as a &lt;strong&gt;Psi Chi chapter president&lt;/strong&gt;, research mentor, and active member of the undergraduate psychology program. I worked to support student scholarship, promote research engagement, and foster an inclusive and collaborative academic environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receiving this award affirmed the importance of leadership beyond academics — emphasizing mentorship, communication, and the ability to build community in research settings. I’m grateful to the faculty and peers who contributed to my growth and success at GVSU.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Summer Scholars Grant Awarded for Belief Change Research (2021)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/student-summer-scholars-grant-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/student-summer-scholars-grant-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Summer 2021, I was awarded a &lt;strong&gt;Student Summer Scholars Grant&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;strong&gt;Office of Undergraduate Research&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt;. This competitive award provided funding and mentorship for students conducting independent research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My funded project, titled&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do Changes in Past Beliefs Influence Current Beliefs?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;br&gt;
was conducted in collaboration with Dr. Michael Wolfe in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt;. It explored how prompting participants to reflect on their prior beliefs before reading persuasive texts impacted their current belief endorsement and argumentative writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grant provided $7,750 in support and included faculty mentorship, presentation opportunities, and professional development workshops. The project culminated in a formal talk at the GVSU Summer Scholars Showcase and served as the foundation for multiple future conference presentations and publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience was a major stepping stone in my development as a researcher and gave me the confidence and skills that ultimately shaped my path toward graduate school.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
