<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Argumentative Writing | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/argumentative-writing/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/argumentative-writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Argumentative Writing</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 10:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Argumentative Writing</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/argumentative-writing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second First-Author Publication: Argumentative Writing and Belief Change in Instructional Science (2024)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/instructional-science-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/instructional-science-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2024, I published my second first-author paper — this time in &lt;em&gt;Instructional Science&lt;/em&gt;, a peer-reviewed journal that focuses on educational psychology and learning processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper, titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Beliefs Influence Argumentative Essay Writing,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
was the culmination of a multi-year undergraduate research project I conducted in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; at Grand Valley State University with Dr. Michael Wolfe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we explored how reading persuasive texts influences students’ beliefs and how those belief changes shape the structure, content, and quality of their argumentative writing. The findings provided empirical evidence that shifts in belief can meaningfully influence written expression — an important insight for both cognitive and educational psychologists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This publication marked a major step forward in translating undergraduate research into peer-reviewed work and solidified my commitment to research on cognition, communication, and belief formation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
