<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Poster Presentation | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/poster-presentation/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/poster-presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Poster Presentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 10:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Poster Presentation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/poster-presentation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting at AHNS 2024: Enhancing PROM Engagement in Head and Neck Cancer</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/midwest-cogsci-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/midwest-cogsci-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2024, I co-presented a research poster at the &lt;strong&gt;American Head and Neck Society (AHNS) Annual Meeting&lt;/strong&gt;, based on work conducted during my time as a Clinical Research Coordinator at &lt;strong&gt;Henry Ford Health&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The poster was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enhancing PROM Engagement: A Mixed Methods Approach to Reminder Interventions and Patient Preferences in Head and Neck Cancer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was part of the &lt;strong&gt;BRIGHT Trial&lt;/strong&gt;, led by Dr. Samantha Tam, and aimed to identify strategies for improving completion rates and patient satisfaction with electronic patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs). My role involved coordinating study visits, managing REDCap data, and contributing to qualitative data synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation marked my first experience disseminating clinical research at a national conference. It offered an important perspective on translational science, bridging patient-centered care and behavioral health research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participating in this work expanded my methodological skills and deepened my appreciation for research that directly impacts patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belief Change and Persuasion: Poster Presentation at MPA 2022</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/mpa-belief-poster-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/mpa-belief-poster-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2022, I presented a poster at the &lt;strong&gt;Midwestern Psychological Association (MPA) Conference&lt;/strong&gt;, held in Chicago. The project was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Information About Past Beliefs Influences Current Beliefs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study explored how explicitly reminding individuals of their past beliefs affects their current evaluations of persuasive information. The poster was based on research I conducted in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; at Grand Valley State University with Dr. Michael Wolfe, and it contributed to our broader line of work on belief change, reading comprehension, and persuasive writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was one of my first in-person academic conferences, and I gained valuable experience discussing research with a broad audience of psychologists and students from across the Midwest. It also reinforced the importance of clear visual communication and thoughtful responses to audience questions — skills I’ve continued to develop in subsequent presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Scholars Day 2022 at GVSU: Belief Change and Persuasion Poster</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-scholars-day-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-scholars-day-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April 2022, I presented a research poster at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University’s Student Scholars Day&lt;/strong&gt;, a campus-wide event that showcases undergraduate research and creative work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My presentation was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Information About Past Beliefs Influences Current Beliefs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project examined how prompting individuals to recall their past beliefs before reading persuasive material could influence how strongly they endorse those beliefs afterward. It was part of my work in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; with Dr. Michael Wolfe and complemented our studies on belief revision and argumentative writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student Scholars Day offered a supportive environment to share work with students, faculty, and staff outside the psychology department. It also gave me an early chance to practice tailoring my research communication for diverse audiences — a skill that has been invaluable throughout my academic path.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Research Experience: Exercise Science Poster at GVSU Student Scholars Day (2019)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-exercise-science-poster-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-exercise-science-poster-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2019, during my first year as an undergraduate at Grand Valley State University, I participated in &lt;strong&gt;Student Scholars Day&lt;/strong&gt; as a co-author on a research poster in the &lt;strong&gt;Exercise Science Lab&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Effect of Different Pre-Exercise Treatments on Power Output.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working under the mentorship of faculty in the Exercise Science program, I helped collect and analyze data examining how various warm-up interventions influenced athletic performance. This early exposure to the research process gave me foundational skills in study design, teamwork, and public presentation — all of which proved valuable as I transitioned into cognitive psychology research later in my undergraduate career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although outside my current academic focus, this project introduced me to the world of empirical inquiry and shaped my confidence in pursuing more complex research in later years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
