<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Undergraduate | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/undergraduate/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/undergraduate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Undergraduate</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 09:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu2517494180984873850.png</url>
      <title>Undergraduate</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/undergraduate/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serving as President of the Psi Chi Chapter at GVSU (2021–2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/psi-chi-president-gvsu-2021-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/psi-chi-president-gvsu-2021-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the 2021–2022 academic year, I served as &lt;strong&gt;President of the Grand Valley State University chapter of Psi Chi&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;International Honor Society in Psychology&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this role, I led a team of officers in organizing academic and professional development events, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graduate school Q&amp;amp;A panels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faculty research spotlights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community service activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peer mentorship pairings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also worked closely with our faculty advisor and departmental leadership to support psychology majors and create an inclusive, engaging chapter culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leadership experience helped me grow in confidence, communication, and organizational skill — all of which have continued to shape my professional identity. Psi Chi gave me a valuable platform to support others and stay deeply engaged in the broader psychology community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduating from Grand Valley State University (2021)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-graduation-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-graduation-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2021, I graduated from &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt; with a &lt;strong&gt;Bachelor of Science in Psychology&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;minor in Applied Statistics&lt;/strong&gt;. My time at GVSU was foundational to my academic and research development — both in and out of the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at GVSU, I was involved in multiple research projects across psychology and exercise science, earned the &lt;strong&gt;Undergraduate Research Scholar designation&lt;/strong&gt;, and completed a &lt;strong&gt;Student Summer Scholars Grant&lt;/strong&gt;. I was also honored to receive several awards, including the &lt;strong&gt;Excellence-in-a-Discipline Award&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;Robert Hendersen Leadership Award&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Outstanding Creative Achievement&lt;/strong&gt; from the Honors College.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through these experiences, I discovered my passion for research on belief, cognition, aging, and emotional memory — and developed a long-term interest in combining psychological science with computational methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GVSU was where I first learned to design studies, analyze data, present at conferences, and write for publication — and it laid the groundwork for everything that followed in graduate school.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
