<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oral Presentation | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/oral-presentation/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/oral-presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Oral Presentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 14:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu2517494180984873850.png</url>
      <title>Oral Presentation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/oral-presentation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting at the Society for Text and Discourse: Beliefs and Argumentative Writing (2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/society-text-discourse-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/society-text-discourse-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Summer 2022, I delivered my first oral presentation at an academic conference — the &lt;strong&gt;Annual Meeting of the Society for Text and Discourse&lt;/strong&gt;. This event, held virtually that year, brought together scholars interested in reading, discourse, and communication processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Belief Change After Reading Predicts Argumentative Essay Content.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research emerged from my work as an undergraduate researcher in the Social Cognition Lab at Grand Valley State University, under the mentorship of Dr. Michael Wolfe. We examined how changes in students&amp;rsquo; beliefs after reading persuasive texts influenced the structure and content of their argumentative essays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenting at this conference was an incredibly formative experience. It helped me build confidence in communicating my research, fielding questions from experts, and engaging with a broader academic community. It also affirmed my interest in pursuing graduate research in cognition, memory, and language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation was an early but pivotal step on my academic path.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Scholars Showcase 2021: Belief Change and Persuasion Talk at GVSU</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-summer-scholars-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-summer-scholars-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Summer 2021, I presented at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University’s Student Summer Scholars Showcase&lt;/strong&gt;, where I shared the results of my research project funded by a competitive undergraduate research grant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk, titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Information About Past Beliefs Influences Current Beliefs,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
explored how reflecting on previously held beliefs shapes the way individuals respond to persuasive texts and influences their reasoning and writing. This was part of my extended work in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; with Dr. Michael Wolfe, supported by the &lt;strong&gt;Student Summer Scholars Grant&lt;/strong&gt; from the Office of Undergraduate Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation was a major milestone in my development as a researcher. It gave me the chance to formally communicate my findings to faculty, administrators, and peers, and marked my first time delivering an academic talk based on independently developed research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience affirmed my desire to pursue graduate study and helped build the skills I continue to use in my current academic and professional presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
