<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Honors College | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/honors-college/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/honors-college/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Honors College</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 13:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Honors College</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/honors-college/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outstanding Creative Achievement Award for Honors College Capstone (2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/creative-achievement-award-podcast-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/creative-achievement-award-podcast-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2022, I was honored to receive the &lt;strong&gt;Outstanding Creative Achievement Award&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;strong&gt;Frederik Meijer Honors College&lt;/strong&gt; at Grand Valley State University. This award recognized the top five senior capstone projects across the college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My project was a podcast series titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perspectives on Psilocybin: The Science and Mysticism of Magic Mushrooms.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series explored the historical, cultural, and scientific dimensions of psilocybin — from indigenous use and psychedelic therapy to neuroscience and public perception. It blended interviews, academic research, and narrative storytelling to bridge science communication and experiential knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This capstone project allowed me to combine academic inquiry with creative storytelling, sparking what would later become a deeper interest in &lt;strong&gt;transformative experiences&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;self-defining memory&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;interdisciplinary communication&lt;/strong&gt; — all of which continue to influence my graduate research trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The award was a meaningful affirmation of the value of creative, public-facing scholarship in psychology and cognitive science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
