<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Milestone | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/milestone/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/milestone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Milestone</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 09:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Milestone</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/milestone/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting My First Year as a Ph.D. Student at Georgia Tech</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/starting-first-year-gt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/starting-first-year-gt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In August 2024, I officially began my first year as a Ph.D. student in the Psychology program at Georgia Tech, with a concentration in Adult Development and Aging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first year is focused on building a strong foundation in cognitive aging, emotion, and memory research while also strengthening my skills in natural language processing. I joined the &lt;strong&gt;Janus Laboratory&lt;/strong&gt;, where I&amp;rsquo;m working with Dr. Hsiao-Wen Liao on projects involving autobiographical memory narratives — particularly how older adults recall emotional high and low points in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also started exploring how large language models like BERT can be used to examine internal vs. external detail, topic diversity, and gist representation in personal narratives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond research, I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed engaging with a new cohort of talented peers, diving into coursework, and beginning to define the focus of my thesis work. It’s been a challenging and inspiring start to what I hope will be a transformative journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to what’s ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted to Georgia Tech&#39;s Psychology Ph.D. Program</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/accepted-to-gradschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/accepted-to-gradschool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2024, I received an offer of admission to the Psychology Ph.D. program at the Georgia Institute of Technology. I&amp;rsquo;ll be specializing in Adult Development and Aging, with a focus on cognitive aging, autobiographical memory, and natural language processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m deeply grateful to be joining the Janus Laboratory, under the mentorship of Dr. Hsiao-Wen Liao. Her work on emotional memory, aging, and narrative structure aligns perfectly with my research interests, and I’m excited to begin contributing to ongoing projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This opportunity represents a major turning point in my academic journey and a chance to grow not only as a researcher but also as a teacher and leader in the field of cognitive science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for future updates as I begin this new chapter in Atlanta!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
