<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AHNS | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/ahns/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/ahns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>AHNS</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 09:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu2517494180984873850.png</url>
      <title>AHNS</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/ahns/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>AHNS at COSM 2024: Socioeconomic Factors and Equity in PROM Completion</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/ahns-cosm-equity-proms-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/ahns-cosm-equity-proms-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In May 2024, I presented a second clinical research poster at the &lt;strong&gt;American Head and Neck Society (AHNS)&lt;/strong&gt; track at &lt;strong&gt;COSM – Combined Otolaryngology Spring Meetings&lt;/strong&gt;. This work was conducted with the research team at &lt;strong&gt;Henry Ford Health&lt;/strong&gt; and focused on equity in cancer care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The poster, titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Socioeconomic Factors Impacting Equity in Completion of Patient-Reported Outcome Measures Among Patients with Head and Neck Cancer,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
investigated how variables like income, insurance status, and digital access affected PROM completion rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I contributed to the data analysis and presentation development alongside collaborators including Dr. Samantha Tam and colleagues across multiple institutions. This work reinforced the need to consider structural barriers in patient engagement and helped me appreciate the broader context of behavioral and psychosocial research within clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COSM was a dynamic, interdisciplinary venue — and presenting our findings there gave me the opportunity to engage with experts in otolaryngology, behavioral medicine, and implementation science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting at AHNS 2024: Enhancing PROM Engagement in Head and Neck Cancer</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/ahns-prom-engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/ahns-prom-engagement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2024, I co-presented a research poster at the &lt;strong&gt;American Head and Neck Society (AHNS) Annual Meeting&lt;/strong&gt;, based on work conducted during my time as a Clinical Research Coordinator at &lt;strong&gt;Henry Ford Health&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The poster was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enhancing PROM Engagement: A Mixed Methods Approach to Reminder Interventions and Patient Preferences in Head and Neck Cancer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was part of the &lt;strong&gt;BRIGHT Trial&lt;/strong&gt;, led by Dr. Samantha Tam, and aimed to identify strategies for improving completion rates and patient satisfaction with electronic patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs). My role involved coordinating study visits, managing REDCap data, and contributing to qualitative data synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation marked my first experience disseminating clinical research at a national conference. It offered an important perspective on translational science, bridging patient-centered care and behavioral health research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participating in this work expanded my methodological skills and deepened my appreciation for research that directly impacts patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
