<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Georgia Tech | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/georgia-tech/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/georgia-tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Georgia Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 09:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Georgia Tech</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/georgia-tech/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing the Cognitive Brain Sciences and Aging Brownbag (2025)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/organizing-brownbag-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/organizing-brownbag-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, I organized the &lt;strong&gt;Cognitive Brain Sciences and Aging Brownbag&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Georgia Institute of Technology&lt;/strong&gt;, a research-focused event series highlighting work across aging, cognition, and neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This student-led forum brought together graduate students and faculty from across labs and departments to share in-progress work, receive feedback, and foster interdisciplinary dialogue. I was responsible for scheduling speakers, coordinating logistics, and promoting engagement within the Georgia Tech psychology community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizing the brownbag helped me build leadership and project management skills while creating space for open and collaborative scientific exchange. It was a rewarding opportunity to support both early-stage researchers and faculty in sharing their ideas and building a research culture grounded in feedback and conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Trip Leader for Outdoor Recreation at Georgia Tech (2025)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/trip-leader-outdoor-rec-gt-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/trip-leader-outdoor-rec-gt-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2025, I became a &lt;strong&gt;Trip Leader for Outdoor Recreation at Georgia Tech&lt;/strong&gt;, a role that combines outdoor education, leadership development, and community engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a trip leader, I help plan and guide excursions such as &lt;strong&gt;rock climbing trips&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;day hikes&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;overnight adventures&lt;/strong&gt; across Georgia and the southeastern U.S. The position involves risk management, technical instruction, group facilitation, and logistics — all while fostering inclusivity and confidence in outdoor spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience has been both personally meaningful and professionally relevant. It has improved my leadership, adaptability, and communication — qualities that translate well to academic teamwork, teaching, and research coordination. It’s also provided balance and renewal alongside the demands of graduate school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outdoor leadership has become a core part of my identity, and I value the opportunity to help others connect with nature, challenge themselves, and grow through shared adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting My First Year as a Ph.D. Student at Georgia Tech</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/starting-first-year-gt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/starting-first-year-gt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In August 2024, I officially began my first year as a Ph.D. student in the Psychology program at Georgia Tech, with a concentration in Adult Development and Aging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first year is focused on building a strong foundation in cognitive aging, emotion, and memory research while also strengthening my skills in natural language processing. I joined the &lt;strong&gt;Janus Laboratory&lt;/strong&gt;, where I&amp;rsquo;m working with Dr. Hsiao-Wen Liao on projects involving autobiographical memory narratives — particularly how older adults recall emotional high and low points in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also started exploring how large language models like BERT can be used to examine internal vs. external detail, topic diversity, and gist representation in personal narratives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond research, I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed engaging with a new cohort of talented peers, diving into coursework, and beginning to define the focus of my thesis work. It’s been a challenging and inspiring start to what I hope will be a transformative journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to what’s ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awarded the President’s Fellowship at Georgia Tech (2024–2028)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/presidents-fellowship-gt-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/presidents-fellowship-gt-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2024, I was honored to receive the &lt;strong&gt;President’s Fellowship&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Georgia Institute of Technology&lt;/strong&gt;, awarded to the &lt;strong&gt;top 10 percent of incoming doctoral students&lt;/strong&gt; across the Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fellowship provides four years of supplemental funding and professional development support. It recognizes not only academic and research potential but also leadership and service contributions. For me, it marked a tremendous vote of confidence in my graduate research goals and my commitment to the study of aging, memory, and emotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This support has given me the flexibility to pursue interdisciplinary work at the intersection of cognitive psychology and natural language processing, and has allowed me to focus deeply on developing both technical and theoretical expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m grateful to Georgia Tech for this opportunity and am working hard to make the most of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted to Georgia Tech&#39;s Psychology Ph.D. Program</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/accepted-to-gradschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/accepted-to-gradschool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2024, I received an offer of admission to the Psychology Ph.D. program at the Georgia Institute of Technology. I&amp;rsquo;ll be specializing in Adult Development and Aging, with a focus on cognitive aging, autobiographical memory, and natural language processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m deeply grateful to be joining the Janus Laboratory, under the mentorship of Dr. Hsiao-Wen Liao. Her work on emotional memory, aging, and narrative structure aligns perfectly with my research interests, and I’m excited to begin contributing to ongoing projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This opportunity represents a major turning point in my academic journey and a chance to grow not only as a researcher but also as a teacher and leader in the field of cognitive science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for future updates as I begin this new chapter in Atlanta!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
