<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Undergraduate Research | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/undergraduate-research/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/undergraduate-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Undergraduate Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 14:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Undergraduate Research</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/undergraduate-research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting at the Society for Text and Discourse: Beliefs and Argumentative Writing (2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/first-publication-educational-gerontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/first-publication-educational-gerontology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Summer 2022, I delivered my first oral presentation at an academic conference — the &lt;strong&gt;Annual Meeting of the Society for Text and Discourse&lt;/strong&gt;. This event, held virtually that year, brought together scholars interested in reading, discourse, and communication processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Belief Change After Reading Predicts Argumentative Essay Content.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research emerged from my work as an undergraduate researcher in the Social Cognition Lab at Grand Valley State University, under the mentorship of Dr. Michael Wolfe. We examined how changes in students&amp;rsquo; beliefs after reading persuasive texts influenced the structure and content of their argumentative essays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenting at this conference was an incredibly formative experience. It helped me build confidence in communicating my research, fielding questions from experts, and engaging with a broader academic community. It also affirmed my interest in pursuing graduate research in cognition, memory, and language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation was an early but pivotal step on my academic path.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belief Change and Persuasion: Poster Presentation at MPA 2022</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/mpa-belief-poster-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/mpa-belief-poster-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2022, I presented a poster at the &lt;strong&gt;Midwestern Psychological Association (MPA) Conference&lt;/strong&gt;, held in Chicago. The project was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Information About Past Beliefs Influences Current Beliefs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study explored how explicitly reminding individuals of their past beliefs affects their current evaluations of persuasive information. The poster was based on research I conducted in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; at Grand Valley State University with Dr. Michael Wolfe, and it contributed to our broader line of work on belief change, reading comprehension, and persuasive writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was one of my first in-person academic conferences, and I gained valuable experience discussing research with a broad audience of psychologists and students from across the Midwest. It also reinforced the importance of clear visual communication and thoughtful responses to audience questions — skills I’ve continued to develop in subsequent presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Scholars Day 2022 at GVSU: Belief Change and Persuasion Poster</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-scholars-day-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-scholars-day-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April 2022, I presented a research poster at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University’s Student Scholars Day&lt;/strong&gt;, a campus-wide event that showcases undergraduate research and creative work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My presentation was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Information About Past Beliefs Influences Current Beliefs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project examined how prompting individuals to recall their past beliefs before reading persuasive material could influence how strongly they endorse those beliefs afterward. It was part of my work in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; with Dr. Michael Wolfe and complemented our studies on belief revision and argumentative writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student Scholars Day offered a supportive environment to share work with students, faculty, and staff outside the psychology department. It also gave me an early chance to practice tailoring my research communication for diverse audiences — a skill that has been invaluable throughout my academic path.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Scholars Showcase 2021: Belief Change and Persuasion Talk at GVSU</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-summer-scholars-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-summer-scholars-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Summer 2021, I presented at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University’s Student Summer Scholars Showcase&lt;/strong&gt;, where I shared the results of my research project funded by a competitive undergraduate research grant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk, titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Information About Past Beliefs Influences Current Beliefs,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
explored how reflecting on previously held beliefs shapes the way individuals respond to persuasive texts and influences their reasoning and writing. This was part of my extended work in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; with Dr. Michael Wolfe, supported by the &lt;strong&gt;Student Summer Scholars Grant&lt;/strong&gt; from the Office of Undergraduate Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation was a major milestone in my development as a researcher. It gave me the chance to formally communicate my findings to faculty, administrators, and peers, and marked my first time delivering an academic talk based on independently developed research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience affirmed my desire to pursue graduate study and helped build the skills I continue to use in my current academic and professional presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Summer Scholars Grant Awarded for Belief Change Research (2021)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/student-summer-scholars-grant-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/student-summer-scholars-grant-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Summer 2021, I was awarded a &lt;strong&gt;Student Summer Scholars Grant&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;strong&gt;Office of Undergraduate Research&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt;. This competitive award provided funding and mentorship for students conducting independent research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My funded project, titled&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do Changes in Past Beliefs Influence Current Beliefs?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;br&gt;
was conducted in collaboration with Dr. Michael Wolfe in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt;. It explored how prompting participants to reflect on their prior beliefs before reading persuasive texts impacted their current belief endorsement and argumentative writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grant provided $7,750 in support and included faculty mentorship, presentation opportunities, and professional development workshops. The project culminated in a formal talk at the GVSU Summer Scholars Showcase and served as the foundation for multiple future conference presentations and publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience was a major stepping stone in my development as a researcher and gave me the confidence and skills that ultimately shaped my path toward graduate school.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Ageism Through Service Learning: Virtual Talk at GVSU Student Scholars Day (2021)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-ageism-virtual-talk-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-ageism-virtual-talk-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2021, I delivered a &lt;strong&gt;virtual talk&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University’s Student Scholars Day&lt;/strong&gt;, presenting findings from an independent study on educational interventions for reducing ageism in college students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Can Ageism Be Reduced by Service Learning Built Into a Lecture-Based Aging Course?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project, conducted under the guidance of Dr. Jing Chen, investigated how a lecture course on aging—when paired with service-learning opportunities—impacted students’ attitudes toward older adults. This research combined my interests in gerontology, education, and social attitudes, and was part of a growing body of work aimed at addressing bias through curriculum design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first formal presentation focused on aging and intergenerational attitudes, and it helped solidify my interest in aging research and its relevance to real-world social issues. The experience also helped me adapt to presenting in virtual formats — a skill that became essential during the pandemic years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Undergraduate Research at GVSU (2018–2019)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/starting-undergrad-research-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/starting-undergrad-research-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Fall 2018, I began my first research experience as an undergraduate student at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt;, joining the &lt;strong&gt;Exercise Science Lab&lt;/strong&gt; during my first year on campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project, titled &lt;em&gt;“The Effect of Different Pre-Exercise Treatments on Power Output,”&lt;/em&gt; investigated how warm-up interventions influence athletic performance. I contributed to data collection, participant coordination, and experimental setup — all of which gave me early exposure to the scientific method and the collaborative nature of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although my academic interests would later shift toward psychology and cognitive science, this experience was a formative milestone. It helped me build confidence in asking research questions, thinking critically about experimental design, and presenting findings — skills that would become central to my later work in psychology, aging, and memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also my first experience presenting research publicly at GVSU’s Student Scholars Day in 2019 — an event that helped launch my passion for research communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
