<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clinical Research | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/clinical-research/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/clinical-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Clinical Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 10:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu2517494180984873850.png</url>
      <title>Clinical Research</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/clinical-research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting at Henry Ford Health Annual Research Symposium: Body Image Distress Intervention (2024)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/henry-ford-symposium-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/henry-ford-symposium-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Fall 2024, I presented a research poster at the &lt;strong&gt;Henry Ford Health Annual Research Symposium&lt;/strong&gt;, based on my work as a Clinical Research Coordinator in the Department of Otolaryngology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The poster was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Effects of a Brief Cognitive Behavioral Treatment vs Attention Control for Body Image-Related Distress Among Head and Neck Cancer Survivors: A Multi-Site RCT.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study was a randomized controlled trial comparing a brief CBT intervention to an attention control condition, aimed at reducing distress related to appearance changes following cancer treatment. I collaborated with a multidisciplinary team across several institutions, contributing to data collection, protocol fidelity, and patient coordination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenting at this internal symposium gave me the chance to share results with clinicians, researchers, and trainees, and to see how local innovations in patient-centered research were making an impact across disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience deepened my interest in clinical trials and behavioral intervention research, especially where psychological science meets real-world application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AHNS at COSM 2024: Socioeconomic Factors and Equity in PROM Completion</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/ahns-cosm-equity-proms-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/ahns-cosm-equity-proms-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In May 2024, I presented a second clinical research poster at the &lt;strong&gt;American Head and Neck Society (AHNS)&lt;/strong&gt; track at &lt;strong&gt;COSM – Combined Otolaryngology Spring Meetings&lt;/strong&gt;. This work was conducted with the research team at &lt;strong&gt;Henry Ford Health&lt;/strong&gt; and focused on equity in cancer care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The poster, titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Socioeconomic Factors Impacting Equity in Completion of Patient-Reported Outcome Measures Among Patients with Head and Neck Cancer,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
investigated how variables like income, insurance status, and digital access affected PROM completion rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I contributed to the data analysis and presentation development alongside collaborators including Dr. Samantha Tam and colleagues across multiple institutions. This work reinforced the need to consider structural barriers in patient engagement and helped me appreciate the broader context of behavioral and psychosocial research within clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COSM was a dynamic, interdisciplinary venue — and presenting our findings there gave me the opportunity to engage with experts in otolaryngology, behavioral medicine, and implementation science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting at AHNS 2024: Enhancing PROM Engagement in Head and Neck Cancer</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/ahns-prom-engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/ahns-prom-engagement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2024, I co-presented a research poster at the &lt;strong&gt;American Head and Neck Society (AHNS) Annual Meeting&lt;/strong&gt;, based on work conducted during my time as a Clinical Research Coordinator at &lt;strong&gt;Henry Ford Health&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The poster was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enhancing PROM Engagement: A Mixed Methods Approach to Reminder Interventions and Patient Preferences in Head and Neck Cancer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was part of the &lt;strong&gt;BRIGHT Trial&lt;/strong&gt;, led by Dr. Samantha Tam, and aimed to identify strategies for improving completion rates and patient satisfaction with electronic patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs). My role involved coordinating study visits, managing REDCap data, and contributing to qualitative data synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation marked my first experience disseminating clinical research at a national conference. It offered an important perspective on translational science, bridging patient-centered care and behavioral health research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participating in this work expanded my methodological skills and deepened my appreciation for research that directly impacts patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Coordinator on the BRIGHT Study at Henry Ford Health (2023)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/bright-study-henry-ford-health-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/bright-study-henry-ford-health-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April 2023, I began working as a &lt;strong&gt;Research Coordinator&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Henry Ford Health&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;BRIGHT Study (Building Resilience in Girls&amp;rsquo; Health Today)&lt;/strong&gt; — a large, longitudinal research project examining &lt;strong&gt;mental health, trauma exposure, and resilience&lt;/strong&gt; in youth populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BRIGHT Study involves multi-wave data collection, including clinical interviews, cognitive assessments, and biological sampling, with a focus on trauma-exposed girls aged 11–17. As a coordinator, I was responsible for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participant scheduling and informed consent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administering and scoring assessments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing REDCap data and IRB documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinating with clinicians, research staff, and school partners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensuring ethical and culturally sensitive practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience offered firsthand insight into &lt;strong&gt;community-based clinical research&lt;/strong&gt; and strengthened my skills in data management, participant rapport, and trauma-informed care. It also affirmed my interest in &lt;strong&gt;lifespan development&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;emotional memory&lt;/strong&gt;, and the ways research can inform interventions and public health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My time on the BRIGHT Study was foundational in preparing for graduate-level work and deepening my commitment to research that supports vulnerable populations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
