<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GVSU | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/gvsu/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/gvsu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>GVSU</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 14:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu2517494180984873850.png</url>
      <title>GVSU</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/gvsu/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excellence-in-a-Discipline Award: Psychology at GVSU (2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/excellence-in-discipline-award-gvsu-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/excellence-in-discipline-award-gvsu-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2022, I was honored to receive the &lt;strong&gt;Excellence-in-a-Discipline Award&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt;, which recognizes one undergraduate student in each major who has demonstrated outstanding academic achievement and disciplinary engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was selected for this award within the &lt;strong&gt;Psychology Department&lt;/strong&gt;, based on my coursework, research contributions, and professional development activities. At the time, I was actively engaged in multiple research projects and had recently presented at both campus and regional conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recognition was a meaningful capstone to my undergraduate work. It reflected not only academic success but also the mentorship, collaboration, and hands-on experiences that shaped my growth as a student and emerging researcher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receiving this award gave me further confidence as I prepared to transition to graduate school and pursue more advanced research opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outstanding Creative Achievement Award for Honors College Capstone (2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/creative-achievement-award-podcast-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/creative-achievement-award-podcast-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2022, I was honored to receive the &lt;strong&gt;Outstanding Creative Achievement Award&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;strong&gt;Frederik Meijer Honors College&lt;/strong&gt; at Grand Valley State University. This award recognized the top five senior capstone projects across the college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My project was a podcast series titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perspectives on Psilocybin: The Science and Mysticism of Magic Mushrooms.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series explored the historical, cultural, and scientific dimensions of psilocybin — from indigenous use and psychedelic therapy to neuroscience and public perception. It blended interviews, academic research, and narrative storytelling to bridge science communication and experiential knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This capstone project allowed me to combine academic inquiry with creative storytelling, sparking what would later become a deeper interest in &lt;strong&gt;transformative experiences&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;self-defining memory&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;interdisciplinary communication&lt;/strong&gt; — all of which continue to influence my graduate research trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The award was a meaningful affirmation of the value of creative, public-facing scholarship in psychology and cognitive science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Hendersen Leadership Award in Psychology (2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/henderson-leadership-award-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/henderson-leadership-award-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2022, I was awarded the &lt;strong&gt;Robert Hendersen Leadership Award&lt;/strong&gt; by the &lt;strong&gt;Psychology Department at Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt;. This departmental honor is presented annually to a student who has demonstrated outstanding leadership, service, and engagement within the academic and campus community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recognition reflected my roles as a &lt;strong&gt;Psi Chi chapter president&lt;/strong&gt;, research mentor, and active member of the undergraduate psychology program. I worked to support student scholarship, promote research engagement, and foster an inclusive and collaborative academic environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receiving this award affirmed the importance of leadership beyond academics — emphasizing mentorship, communication, and the ability to build community in research settings. I’m grateful to the faculty and peers who contributed to my growth and success at GVSU.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Scholars Day 2022 at GVSU: Belief Change and Persuasion Poster</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-scholars-day-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-scholars-day-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April 2022, I presented a research poster at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University’s Student Scholars Day&lt;/strong&gt;, a campus-wide event that showcases undergraduate research and creative work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My presentation was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Information About Past Beliefs Influences Current Beliefs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project examined how prompting individuals to recall their past beliefs before reading persuasive material could influence how strongly they endorse those beliefs afterward. It was part of my work in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; with Dr. Michael Wolfe and complemented our studies on belief revision and argumentative writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student Scholars Day offered a supportive environment to share work with students, faculty, and staff outside the psychology department. It also gave me an early chance to practice tailoring my research communication for diverse audiences — a skill that has been invaluable throughout my academic path.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serving as President of the Psi Chi Chapter at GVSU (2021–2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/psi-chi-president-gvsu-2021-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/psi-chi-president-gvsu-2021-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the 2021–2022 academic year, I served as &lt;strong&gt;President of the Grand Valley State University chapter of Psi Chi&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;International Honor Society in Psychology&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this role, I led a team of officers in organizing academic and professional development events, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graduate school Q&amp;amp;A panels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faculty research spotlights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community service activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peer mentorship pairings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also worked closely with our faculty advisor and departmental leadership to support psychology majors and create an inclusive, engaging chapter culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leadership experience helped me grow in confidence, communication, and organizational skill — all of which have continued to shape my professional identity. Psi Chi gave me a valuable platform to support others and stay deeply engaged in the broader psychology community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Scholars Showcase 2021: Belief Change and Persuasion Talk at GVSU</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-summer-scholars-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-summer-scholars-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Summer 2021, I presented at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University’s Student Summer Scholars Showcase&lt;/strong&gt;, where I shared the results of my research project funded by a competitive undergraduate research grant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk, titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Information About Past Beliefs Influences Current Beliefs,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
explored how reflecting on previously held beliefs shapes the way individuals respond to persuasive texts and influences their reasoning and writing. This was part of my extended work in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; with Dr. Michael Wolfe, supported by the &lt;strong&gt;Student Summer Scholars Grant&lt;/strong&gt; from the Office of Undergraduate Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation was a major milestone in my development as a researcher. It gave me the chance to formally communicate my findings to faculty, administrators, and peers, and marked my first time delivering an academic talk based on independently developed research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience affirmed my desire to pursue graduate study and helped build the skills I continue to use in my current academic and professional presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Summer Scholars Grant Awarded for Belief Change Research (2021)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/student-summer-scholars-grant-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/student-summer-scholars-grant-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Summer 2021, I was awarded a &lt;strong&gt;Student Summer Scholars Grant&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;strong&gt;Office of Undergraduate Research&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt;. This competitive award provided funding and mentorship for students conducting independent research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My funded project, titled&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do Changes in Past Beliefs Influence Current Beliefs?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;br&gt;
was conducted in collaboration with Dr. Michael Wolfe in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt;. It explored how prompting participants to reflect on their prior beliefs before reading persuasive texts impacted their current belief endorsement and argumentative writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grant provided $7,750 in support and included faculty mentorship, presentation opportunities, and professional development workshops. The project culminated in a formal talk at the GVSU Summer Scholars Showcase and served as the foundation for multiple future conference presentations and publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience was a major stepping stone in my development as a researcher and gave me the confidence and skills that ultimately shaped my path toward graduate school.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduating from Grand Valley State University (2021)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-graduation-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-graduation-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2021, I graduated from &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt; with a &lt;strong&gt;Bachelor of Science in Psychology&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;minor in Applied Statistics&lt;/strong&gt;. My time at GVSU was foundational to my academic and research development — both in and out of the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at GVSU, I was involved in multiple research projects across psychology and exercise science, earned the &lt;strong&gt;Undergraduate Research Scholar designation&lt;/strong&gt;, and completed a &lt;strong&gt;Student Summer Scholars Grant&lt;/strong&gt;. I was also honored to receive several awards, including the &lt;strong&gt;Excellence-in-a-Discipline Award&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;Robert Hendersen Leadership Award&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Outstanding Creative Achievement&lt;/strong&gt; from the Honors College.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through these experiences, I discovered my passion for research on belief, cognition, aging, and emotional memory — and developed a long-term interest in combining psychological science with computational methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GVSU was where I first learned to design studies, analyze data, present at conferences, and write for publication — and it laid the groundwork for everything that followed in graduate school.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Ageism Through Service Learning: Virtual Talk at GVSU Student Scholars Day (2021)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-ageism-virtual-talk-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-ageism-virtual-talk-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2021, I delivered a &lt;strong&gt;virtual talk&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University’s Student Scholars Day&lt;/strong&gt;, presenting findings from an independent study on educational interventions for reducing ageism in college students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Can Ageism Be Reduced by Service Learning Built Into a Lecture-Based Aging Course?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project, conducted under the guidance of Dr. Jing Chen, investigated how a lecture course on aging—when paired with service-learning opportunities—impacted students’ attitudes toward older adults. This research combined my interests in gerontology, education, and social attitudes, and was part of a growing body of work aimed at addressing bias through curriculum design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first formal presentation focused on aging and intergenerational attitudes, and it helped solidify my interest in aging research and its relevance to real-world social issues. The experience also helped me adapt to presenting in virtual formats — a skill that became essential during the pandemic years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Research Experience: Exercise Science Poster at GVSU Student Scholars Day (2019)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-exercise-science-poster-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/gvsu-exercise-science-poster-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2019, during my first year as an undergraduate at Grand Valley State University, I participated in &lt;strong&gt;Student Scholars Day&lt;/strong&gt; as a co-author on a research poster in the &lt;strong&gt;Exercise Science Lab&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Effect of Different Pre-Exercise Treatments on Power Output.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working under the mentorship of faculty in the Exercise Science program, I helped collect and analyze data examining how various warm-up interventions influenced athletic performance. This early exposure to the research process gave me foundational skills in study design, teamwork, and public presentation — all of which proved valuable as I transitioned into cognitive psychology research later in my undergraduate career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although outside my current academic focus, this project introduced me to the world of empirical inquiry and shaped my confidence in pursuing more complex research in later years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Undergraduate Research at GVSU (2018–2019)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/starting-undergrad-research-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/starting-undergrad-research-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Fall 2018, I began my first research experience as an undergraduate student at &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt;, joining the &lt;strong&gt;Exercise Science Lab&lt;/strong&gt; during my first year on campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project, titled &lt;em&gt;“The Effect of Different Pre-Exercise Treatments on Power Output,”&lt;/em&gt; investigated how warm-up interventions influence athletic performance. I contributed to data collection, participant coordination, and experimental setup — all of which gave me early exposure to the scientific method and the collaborative nature of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although my academic interests would later shift toward psychology and cognitive science, this experience was a formative milestone. It helped me build confidence in asking research questions, thinking critically about experimental design, and presenting findings — skills that would become central to my later work in psychology, aging, and memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also my first experience presenting research publicly at GVSU’s Student Scholars Day in 2019 — an event that helped launch my passion for research communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
