<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Coordinator | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/research-coordinator/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/research-coordinator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Research Coordinator</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 09:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Research Coordinator</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/research-coordinator/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Coordinator on the BRIGHT Study at Henry Ford Health (2023)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/bright-study-henry-ford-health-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/bright-study-henry-ford-health-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April 2023, I began working as a &lt;strong&gt;Research Coordinator&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Henry Ford Health&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;BRIGHT Study (Building Resilience in Girls&amp;rsquo; Health Today)&lt;/strong&gt; — a large, longitudinal research project examining &lt;strong&gt;mental health, trauma exposure, and resilience&lt;/strong&gt; in youth populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BRIGHT Study involves multi-wave data collection, including clinical interviews, cognitive assessments, and biological sampling, with a focus on trauma-exposed girls aged 11–17. As a coordinator, I was responsible for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participant scheduling and informed consent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administering and scoring assessments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing REDCap data and IRB documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinating with clinicians, research staff, and school partners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensuring ethical and culturally sensitive practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience offered firsthand insight into &lt;strong&gt;community-based clinical research&lt;/strong&gt; and strengthened my skills in data management, participant rapport, and trauma-informed care. It also affirmed my interest in &lt;strong&gt;lifespan development&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;emotional memory&lt;/strong&gt;, and the ways research can inform interventions and public health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My time on the BRIGHT Study was foundational in preparing for graduate-level work and deepening my commitment to research that supports vulnerable populations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
