<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Outdoor Education | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/outdoor-education/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/outdoor-education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Outdoor Education</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu2517494180984873850.png</url>
      <title>Outdoor Education</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/outdoor-education/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Trip Leader for Outdoor Recreation at Georgia Tech (2025)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2025-trip_leader_orgt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2025-trip_leader_orgt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2025, I became a &lt;strong&gt;Trip Leader for Outdoor Recreation at Georgia Tech&lt;/strong&gt;, a role that combines outdoor education, leadership development, and community engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a trip leader, I help plan and guide excursions such as &lt;strong&gt;rock climbing trips&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;day hikes&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;overnight adventures&lt;/strong&gt; across Georgia and the southeastern U.S. The position involves risk management, technical instruction, group facilitation, and logistics — all while fostering inclusivity and confidence in outdoor spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience has been both personally meaningful and professionally relevant. It has improved my leadership, adaptability, and communication — qualities that translate well to academic teamwork, teaching, and research coordination. It’s also provided balance and renewal alongside the demands of graduate school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outdoor leadership has become a core part of my identity, and I value the opportunity to help others connect with nature, challenge themselves, and grow through shared adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
