<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psychology | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/psychology/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Psychology</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 14:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Psychology</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/psychology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excellence-in-a-Discipline Award: Psychology at GVSU (2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/excellence-in-discipline-award-gvsu-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/excellence-in-discipline-award-gvsu-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2022, I was honored to receive the &lt;strong&gt;Excellence-in-a-Discipline Award&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt;, which recognizes one undergraduate student in each major who has demonstrated outstanding academic achievement and disciplinary engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was selected for this award within the &lt;strong&gt;Psychology Department&lt;/strong&gt;, based on my coursework, research contributions, and professional development activities. At the time, I was actively engaged in multiple research projects and had recently presented at both campus and regional conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recognition was a meaningful capstone to my undergraduate work. It reflected not only academic success but also the mentorship, collaboration, and hands-on experiences that shaped my growth as a student and emerging researcher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receiving this award gave me further confidence as I prepared to transition to graduate school and pursue more advanced research opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Hendersen Leadership Award in Psychology (2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/henderson-leadership-award-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/henderson-leadership-award-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2022, I was awarded the &lt;strong&gt;Robert Hendersen Leadership Award&lt;/strong&gt; by the &lt;strong&gt;Psychology Department at Grand Valley State University&lt;/strong&gt;. This departmental honor is presented annually to a student who has demonstrated outstanding leadership, service, and engagement within the academic and campus community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recognition reflected my roles as a &lt;strong&gt;Psi Chi chapter president&lt;/strong&gt;, research mentor, and active member of the undergraduate psychology program. I worked to support student scholarship, promote research engagement, and foster an inclusive and collaborative academic environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receiving this award affirmed the importance of leadership beyond academics — emphasizing mentorship, communication, and the ability to build community in research settings. I’m grateful to the faculty and peers who contributed to my growth and success at GVSU.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serving as President of the Psi Chi Chapter at GVSU (2021–2022)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/psi-chi-president-gvsu-2021-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/psi-chi-president-gvsu-2021-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the 2021–2022 academic year, I served as &lt;strong&gt;President of the Grand Valley State University chapter of Psi Chi&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;International Honor Society in Psychology&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this role, I led a team of officers in organizing academic and professional development events, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graduate school Q&amp;amp;A panels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faculty research spotlights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community service activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peer mentorship pairings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also worked closely with our faculty advisor and departmental leadership to support psychology majors and create an inclusive, engaging chapter culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leadership experience helped me grow in confidence, communication, and organizational skill — all of which have continued to shape my professional identity. Psi Chi gave me a valuable platform to support others and stay deeply engaged in the broader psychology community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
