<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grand Valley State University | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/grand-valley-state-university/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/grand-valley-state-university/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Grand Valley State University</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 10:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu2517494180984873850.png</url>
      <title>Grand Valley State University</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/grand-valley-state-university/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Psych Friends Peer Mentor at Grand Valley State University (2024)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/psych-friends-peer-mentor-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/psych-friends-peer-mentor-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Fall 2021, I joined &lt;strong&gt;Psych Friends&lt;/strong&gt;, a peer mentoring program in the &lt;strong&gt;Grand Valley State University Department of Psychology&lt;/strong&gt;, as an &lt;strong&gt;upper-division psychology major mentor&lt;/strong&gt;. This program connects experienced psychology students with those newer to the major to foster academic success, well-being, and a sense of community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a mentor, I’ve guided mentees on major requirements, career and education paths in psychology, strategies for academic success, and self-care techniques. I’ve also shared insights on the graduate school application process and helped mentees explore the diverse opportunities within the field of psychology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psych Friends has been a fulfilling experience that aligns with my passion for mentorship and community building. It’s been rewarding to support others in navigating their academic journey, just as I was supported when I started mine. I’m grateful for the opportunity to contribute to the growth and success of my peers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
