<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publication | Liam W. Hart</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/publication/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Publication</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 10:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Publication</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tags/publication/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Publication: Belief Verification and Current Beliefs in The Open Psychology Journal (2024)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/open-psychology-journal-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/open-psychology-journal-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2024, I co-authored a publication in &lt;em&gt;The Open Psychology Journal&lt;/em&gt; titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Verification of Past Beliefs Influences Current Beliefs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project built on a series of studies investigating the cognitive mechanisms involved in belief revision. Specifically, we examined how the process of retrieving and verifying one’s past beliefs can affect present-day belief strength, even in light of conflicting evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work was done in collaboration with Dr. Michael Wolfe, along with G. Russell, T. Williams, and myself. It was part of our broader effort to understand how metacognitive processes—like reflecting on prior knowledge—affect reasoning and writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper contributed to the growing literature on belief change and belief coherence, and it offered implications for educational practice, persuasive communication, and critical thinking training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was rewarding to see this collaborative work published and to contribute to a line of research that bridges cognition, memory, and communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second First-Author Publication: Argumentative Writing and Belief Change in Instructional Science (2024)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/instructional-science-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/instructional-science-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2024, I published my second first-author paper — this time in &lt;em&gt;Instructional Science&lt;/em&gt;, a peer-reviewed journal that focuses on educational psychology and learning processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper, titled:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Beliefs Influence Argumentative Essay Writing,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
was the culmination of a multi-year undergraduate research project I conducted in the &lt;strong&gt;Social Cognition Lab&lt;/strong&gt; at Grand Valley State University with Dr. Michael Wolfe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we explored how reading persuasive texts influences students’ beliefs and how those belief changes shape the structure, content, and quality of their argumentative writing. The findings provided empirical evidence that shifts in belief can meaningfully influence written expression — an important insight for both cognitive and educational psychologists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This publication marked a major step forward in translating undergraduate research into peer-reviewed work and solidified my commitment to research on cognition, communication, and belief formation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First First-Author Publication: Educational Gerontology (2023)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/first-publication-educational-gerontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/first-publication-educational-gerontology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2023, I had the honor of publishing my first first-author paper in &lt;em&gt;Educational Gerontology&lt;/em&gt;, based on research I conducted as an undergraduate student at Grand Valley State University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study explored whether a lecture-based aging course with a service-learning component could positively influence college students&amp;rsquo; attitudes toward older adults. I worked closely with Dr. Jing Chen to design and analyze the project, which was inspired by our shared interest in reducing ageism through educational interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publishing this paper marked a major personal and professional milestone. It taught me how to take a project from early design through peer review and helped build the foundation for my continued research focus on aging, emotion, and memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the paper here:&lt;br&gt;
📄 &lt;em&gt;Can a course on aging with a service-learning component change students’ attitudes toward aging?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Published in &lt;em&gt;Educational Gerontology&lt;/em&gt;, 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
